## **András Gémes**

## **Summary**

Embedded software engineer with 7 years of experience and a strong interest in cybersecurity, with <a href="hands-on experience">hands-on experience</a> in malware analysis and reverse engineering (e.g., ransomware, loaders and botnets). Certified in <a href="Sec+">Sec+</a>, <a href="CASP+/SecX">CASP+/SecX</a>, <a href="CEH">CEH</a>, <a href="IMBT">IMBT</a> and <a href="PMAT">PMAT</a>. Looking to apply my technical expertise and security skills in a malware analyst or reverse engineer role.

## Work experience

#### **Rust Software Engineer**

Feb 2023 - Present

HighTec EDV-Systeme GmbH - Budapest, Hungary

- Implementing Rust and assembly tests for the Rust compiler
- · Hardening the Rust toolchain binaries against reverse engineering
- Representing HighTec as a member of the LLVM security group

### **Embedded Software Engineer**

May 2018 – Jan 2023

*Knorr-Bremse - Budapest, Hungary* 

- Implemented, automated and evaluated static application security testing (SAST)
- Configured and hardened memory and real-time operating system (RTOS) software modules
- Investigated and debugged critical software issues at the assembly level

#### **Skills**

Languages: C, Rust, Python 3, Assembly (ARM64/AArch64, AMD64/x86-64), Bash

Malware analysis (static): Ghidra, IDA, capa, YARA, DiE, dnSpy, readelf, objdump

Malware analysis (dynamic): GDB, LLDB, QEMU, strace, eBPF, VirtualBox, Qiling, Frida, x64dbg, Sysinternals

Network analysis and protocols: Wireshark, Suricata, Zeek, FakeNet-NG, INetSim, TCP, UDP, HTTP, HTTPS, DNS

Platforms and DevOps tools: Linux (Fedora, Ubuntu), Windows, Git, Docker, GitHub Actions, Jenkins

Embedded systems and protocols: STM32, ESP32, AURIX, Wi-Fi, CAN, SPI, UART, I2C

#### **Certifications**

CompTIA Security+, CompTIA CASP+/SecurityX, EC-Council CEH, Invoke RE IMBT and TCM Security PMAT

# **Relevant projects**

- ghidra: contributing bug reports and patches to Ghidra, focusing on the BSim, Debugger and FunctionID features
- ghidra-scripts: implementing custom Ghidra scripts to support malware analysis
- rustbininfo: submitting various improvements targeting the compiler version and dependency guesser
- shadow-shell: developing a cyber lab for shellcode analysis, using Assembly and C

#### **Education**

#### **MSc in Mechatronics Engineering**

Feb 2016 - June 2018

Budapest University of Technology and Economics - Budapest, Hungary

#### **BSc in Mechatronics Engineering**

Sept 2012 - Jan 2016

*University of Pannonia - Veszprém, Hungary* 

#### **Continuous education**

I am actively learning on Maldev Academy and TryHackMe, reading Blue Fox: Arm Assembly and managing my homelab.